Guide to the Thomas C. Moser Papers SC0709
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Thomas C. Moser papers
1892-2002
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Moser, Thomas C.
SC0709
42 Linear Feet
Papers reflect his career as scholar and teacher at Stanford University. Included are class files, lectures, drafts of articles and reviews, administrative files, and correspondence. There are also files on student unrest of the late 60s and early 70s.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research. Accession 2012-083 boxes 4 and 5 contain student grades and promotion/tenure files. These boxes are restricted until January 1, 2072.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor Emeritus of English at Stanford University, Moser earned his Ph.D. at Harvard in 1955. He taught at Wellesley before joining the Stanford faculty. His published works include Wuthering Heights: Text, Sources, Criticism (1962); Lord Jim; an Authoritative Text (1968); and The Life in the Fiction of Ford Madox Ford (1980).
Description of the Collection
Papers reflect his career as scholar and teacher at Stanford University. Included are class files, lectures, drafts of articles and reviews, administrative files, and correspondence. There are also files on student unrest of the late 60s and early 70s.
English literature -- Study and teaching.; American literature -- Study and teaching.; Student movements -- California.; Moser, Thomas C.; Moser, Thomas C.; Moser, Thomas C.; Stanford University. Department of English
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2002-053
  - Bay Area student and alternative newspapers, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Sit-In 1968-70 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Sit-In New Left (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - [Newspapers, memos, etc. re student political activities, 1971] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - [Newspapers, memos, etc. re student political activities], 1972-73 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Turmoil, 1971-72 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Times Literary Supplement on Crit & America (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - CEA (College English Association) 1964-65 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - CEASFBR: President, 1963-64. C. C. Olson (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - An Outcast – afterword and correspondence (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Norton [publisher] correspondence, 1964-67 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Conradiana Newsletters (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Look Homeward, Angel – paper by Moser on Thomas Wolfe book, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Wuthering Heights: Text and Criticism – article and correspondence, 1962-63 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Re Norton, Lord Jim (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Look Homeward, Angel - notes (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - The Characters of Thomas Wolfe (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Bronte paper – drafts, correspondence, 1959-61 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Conrad: Achievement and Decline – correspondence, notes, etc. 1955-58 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Reviews – readers' reports (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Blondel translation – article, correspondence, 1962-63 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - The Rescue (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The Sisters (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Class notes: Nigger, Youth, HD, Typhoon (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Notes on critical books and some C articles (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Conrad on writing (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Conrad's letters (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Rescuer photostats (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Reviews – drafts, correspondence, 1958-63 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Job correspondence (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Advanced placement examinations (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Advanced placement talks & CEEB (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Committee on Freshmen Instruction, 1960-61 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Photocopies of original sources [a variety of diaries/journals?- 8 bundles] (Box 2)
  - U.M.I. – 2 (correspondence) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - AAUP (Moser – personal), 1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Ph.D. candidate [proposals, exam schedules, etc.] (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Moser's correspondence, 1959-62 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Humanities Honors program (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Headship and Dean Allen (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Talks to Freshmen (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Talks – to alums, grad students, introductions (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Department of English (SU) – correspondence and other things (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - English 1A, Section 3, Fall 1970 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Stanford-in-France, report on (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - English 1, Section 10, Autumn 1965 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Freshmen English, Winter 1968 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Freshmen English, section 18, Winter 1966-67 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - English 196 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Freshmen English assignments (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Comp Lit 362 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - English 370 American Novel (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - English 75 – Syllabi, tests, etc. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Sample themes (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Voice Project File 1966-67 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - English 195 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Senior Colloquia 192 – Faulkner, Summer 1967 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - English 155 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - English 370 American Fiction (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Cry the Beloved Country – notes on (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Norris – Responsibilities of the Novelist (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - English 370 20th century American Fiction (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Nabokov (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Department and University, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Department and University, 1984-85 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - University, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Grads, 1985-86 [may need to be checked for restricted materials] (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Undergrads, 1984-85 [review for restrictions] (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Grads, 1984-85 [may need to be checked for restricted materials] (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Personal 1980-83 (correspondence) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Personal 1965-67 (correspondence) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Personal 1963-64 (correspondence) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Personal 1985-86 (correspondence) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Moser, confidential [review for restrictions] (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - English 1971-74 (departmental??) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - CEASFBR 2 (College English Association), 1965 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Freshman Seminar 31 – Twain/Faulkner, Winter 1978-79 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - English 155 – Conrad & Faulkner, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Poems by Frost, Dickinson, Robinson [class handouts] (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - English 122 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - English 100F (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - English 158B/258B Mark Twain & Henry James (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - English 234F American fiction 1917-1940 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - English 381d – James, Summer1967 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - English 381a James, Conrad, Ford (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - English 381 James, Conrad, Ford (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - English English 381 James, Conrad, Ford (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - English 269 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - English 362B, 1973-74 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Yalom & Yalom: Lit & Psych Seminar (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - The Double – Moser & Hoffman [not a class file] (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - English 166 – Conrad seminar (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - English 155, Spring 1968 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - English 196B Honors seminar, Autumn 1976 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - English 385E, James Seminar, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - FS 8a & b, Lilt. & Psych 1975-76 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - English 387 James, Conrad, Ford (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Yalom: Freud (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Sears: Dynamic (?) Psych & papers (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Scholarly business 1984-88 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Undergrads 1995-99 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - U.M.I. – 1+ (correspondence) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - U.M.I. – 1 (correspondence) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Undergrads 1986-88 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Undergrads 1989 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Grads 1986-88 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - University 1987-1988 Sept. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - [2 papers: From Olive Garnett's Diary: Impressions of Ford Madox Ford and his Friends, 189-1906 (by Moser?); and Existential Skepticism in Joseph Conrad's Moral Code by Helen L. Guerrant, 1960] (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Conrad and Ford letters to Keating (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Term papers on Ford (by various SU students) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Teaching Lord Jim - lectures (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Good Soldier article – first draft (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Good Soldier article – second draft (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Good Soldier article – final draft (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Clippings on Conrad and Ford [also notes & articles] (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Bibliography (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Dr. Meyer on Ford and Conrad (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Report on MS (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Ford and Marshall to Walpole (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Ford to Anthony Bertram and to Herbert Read [copies] (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Ford to Jerrold [copies] (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Structure of Nostromo (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Undergrads 1994-95 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Undergrads 1991-92 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Paste ups of photocopies of Lord Jim criticism & scholarship and proof sheets for Moser's Norton Critical Edition of Lord Jim (1968) (Box 8)
  - Restricted folders removed:
    - Tenure file on Barbara Gelpi (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Moser's letters of recommendation (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2005-123
  - Olive R. Garnett Diary, 1889-1952
    - 1889-July 1890 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1890 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - May 1891-Christmas (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - February 24-March 31, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1892 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - June 28-November 1, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - November 9-December 7, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - December 10, 1892- January 29, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - February 1-March 15, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - March 16-April 29, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - April 23-June 14, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - June 15-July 18, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - July 19-September, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - September 6-October 21, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - November 12, 1893-January 30, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - February 1-March 16, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - March 19-May 20, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - June 5-July 23, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - July 24-December 31, 1894 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - January 3-March 22, 1895 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - March 25-May 27, 1895 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - June 14-September 30, 1895 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - October 22, 1895-May 15, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - after 1895 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - October 9-December 31, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - March 24, 1900-June 1903 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - January 1, 1901-June 11, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - June 12, 1903-April 11, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - April 12, 1905-April 1, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - August 3, 1907-May 31, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - June 1, 1911-March 26, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - April 22, 1914-September 1917 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - September 1917-January 1918 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - May 1920-1922 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - (including clippings), 1923-1933 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - 1946-1949 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 1951 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 1952 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - (including poetry), 1957 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Olive R. Garnett Diary (duplicates), 1889-1952
    - 1890 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - May 1891-Christmas (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - February 24-March 31, 1892 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - 1892 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - June 28-November 1, 1892 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - November 9-December 7, 1892 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - December 10, 1892- January 29, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - February 1-March 15, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - March 16-April 29, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - April 23-June 14, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - June 15-July 18, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - July 19-September, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - September 6-October 21, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - November 12, 1893-January 30, 1894 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - February 1-March 16, 1894 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - March 19-May 20, 1894 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - June 5-July 23, 1894 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - July 24-December 31, 1894 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - January 3-March 22, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - March 25-May 27, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - June 14-September 30, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - October 22, 1895-May 15, 1896 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - after 1895 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - October 9-December 31, 1899 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - March 24, 1900-June 1903 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - January 1, 1901-June 11, 1903 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - June 12, 1903-April 11, 1905 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - April 12, 1905-April 1, 1907 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - August 3, 1907-May 31, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - June 1, 1911-March 26, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - April 22, 1914-September 1917 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - September 1917-January 1918 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Anne Michele’s Olive (correspondence and research notes) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Garnett diary-full version of volume XXI, 1893 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Full length Olive (notes on Olive Garnett, Ford Madox Hueffer) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Typed excerpts from Garnett’s diary (with editorial notes), folder 1/3 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Typed excerpts from Garnett’s diary (with editorial notes), folder 2/3 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Typed excerpts from Garnett’s diary (with editorial notes, photograph) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Moser’s impression of Ford Madox and friends (article) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, research materials, photographs (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Research materials (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with publisher, research materials (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Research materials (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Photographs (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Transcribed correspondence, Garnett research (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence and “Papers of the Eighth Internationals Conference of (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Maps, letters from publisher (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - In Russia’s Night (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Graduates, 1989-1992 folder 1/4 (student papers, correspondence) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Graduates, 1989-1992 (reference letters, correspondence, paper), folder (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Graduates, 1989-1992 (reference letters, correspondence), folder 3/4 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Graduates, 1989-1992 (correspondence), folder 4/4 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Undergrads, 1990-1991 (reference letters, correspondence), folder 1/3 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Undergrads, 1990-1991 (reference letters, correspondence), folder 2/3 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Undergrads, 1990-1991 (scholarship information, correspondence), folder (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Undergrads, 1992-1994 (student papers, correspondence), folder 1/4 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Undergrads, 1992-1994 (correspondence, essay by professor (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Undergrads, 1992-1994 (correspondence, photographs), folder 3/4 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Undergrads, 1992-1994 (student papers, correspondence), folder 4/4 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Graduates, 1992-1995 (correspondence, photographs), folder 1/4 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Graduates, 1992-1995 (correspondence), folder 2/4 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Graduates, 1992-1995 (student papers, correspondence), folder 3/4 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Graduates, 1992-1995 (reference letters, correspondence), folder 4/4 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Graduate Studies Committee, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - University, October, 1988-1991 (correspondence), folder 1/4 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - University, October, 1988-1991 (correspondence, department budget) (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - University, October 1988-1991 (correspondence, department budget) (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - University, October 1988-1991 (correspondence, miscellaneous), folder (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - University, 1991-1994 (correspondence, fellowship information), folder (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - University, 1991-1994 (correspondence), folder 2/3 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - University, 1991-1994 (correspondence), folder 3/3 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Associates of Stanford University library 1 (correspondence), folder 1/3 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Associates of Stanford University library 1 (correspondence), folder 2/3 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Associates of Stanford University library 1 (correspondence (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Associates of Stanford University library 2 (annual report, memoranda) (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Associates of Stanford University library 2 (miscellaneous), folder 2/4 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Associates of Stanford University library 2 (correspondence), folder 3/4 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Associates of Stanford University library 2 (annual report (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Stanford University library collections, noted donations), folder 4/4 (Box not specified)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Joseph Conrad: Achievement and Decline (typescript), folder 1/6 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Joseph Conrad: Achievement and Decline (typescript), folder 2/6 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Joseph Conrad: Achievement and Decline (typescript), folder 3/6 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Joseph Conrad: Achievement and Decline (typescript), folder 4/6 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Joseph Conrad: Achievement and Decline (typescript), folder 5/6 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Joseph Conrad: Achievement and Decline (typescript), folder 6/6 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Manuscript by Moser (Wuthering Heights), folder 1/9 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Manuscript by Moser (Wuthering Heights), folder 2/9 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Manuscript by Moser (Wuthering Heights), folder 3/9 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Manuscript by Moser (Wuthering Heights), folder 4/9 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Manuscript by Moser (Wuthering Heights), folder 5/9 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Manuscript by Moser (Wuthering Heights), folder 6/9 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Manuscript by Moser (Wuthering Heights), folder 7/9 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Manuscript by Moser (Wuthering Heights), folder 8/9 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Manuscript by Moser (Wuthering Heights), folder 9/9 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - John Hawke-reading at Stanford University, 1972; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - John Hawke-reading at Stanford University, 1973; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - John Hawke-reading at Stanford University, 1973; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Albert Guerard-reading at Stanford University, 1973; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Stanford University in France, 1963; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Wellesley Tupelos, 1956; 1 audio disc(s) (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Course material (index cards)-4 boxes (Box 13)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2007-152
  - Correspondence files (mostly 1980s):
    - Hawkes, John (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Old Friends (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Guerard, Albert J. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ford [with a variety of people about Ford Madox Ford] (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Gelpi, Albert and Barbara (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Family (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Levin, David (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Watt, Ian (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Evans, Gomer (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Stegner, Wallace (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Winters, Yvor [his response to 1965 department questionnaire on proposed Institute for Literary Studies] (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Garnett, David (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Conrad [with a variety of people about Conrad and Moser's pubs, talks, etc.] (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Lowrie, Rachel Moodie (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Restricted (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Faulkner '86- [with a variety of people about Faulker and Moser's pubs, talks, etc.] (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Faulkner '79- [with a variety of people about Faulker and Moser's pubs, talks, etc.] (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Moser/Watt correspondence 1968-89 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Moser/Watt correspondence 1981-87 with articles (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Moser & Watt offprints (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Personal correspondence 1987/88 (Box 2)
    - Personal correspondence 1990 (Box 2)
    - Personal correspondence 1991-92 (Box 2)
    - Personal correspondence 1993-94 (Box 2)
    - Personal correspondence 1995-96 (Box 2)
    - Letters re Ford book & reviews 1981 (Box 2)
    - Faulkner stuff – conferences, bibliography, clippings (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Notes on Blotner, Stone, Honneghausen (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Notions (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Poems [Faulkner] – index, Berg, HRC, notes (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Faulkner interviews, correspondence by and about (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Early prose (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Soldiers Pay (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Elmer – notes and text (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Mosquitos - notes (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Mississippi poems (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Flags in the Dust (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Father Abraham (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Old Colonel (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Conrad Panel – MLA 1986 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Conrad / Ford / Garrett misc. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Conrad / Ford / Garrett misc. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Conrad / Ford / Garrett misc. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Conrad / Ford / Garrett misc. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Galleys for Lord Jim (Norton critical edition) (Box 4)
    - Issues of The Conradian and The Conradiana (Box 4)
    - Set of bibliography cards on Conrad (Box 4)
    - Wynn Collection of Faulkner poetry, photocopies from (Box 4)
    - Packet of correspondence and other materials on Marwood (Box 4)
    - Packet of correspondence, interview notes on F. M. Ford (Box 4)
    - Packet of correspondence, interview notes on Conrad (Box 4)
    - Packet of letters from Anne Mitchell in England (Box 4)
    - Packet: English Department retreat materials 1990 (Box 5)
    - Packet: Curriculum Committee (Box 5)
    - Packet: English 396 Intro to Graduate Studies (Box 5)
    - Packet: Graduate student papers on Faulkner (Box 5)
    - Packet: Student papers on James (Box 5)
    - Packet: Student papers on Faulkner (Box 5)
    - Packet: Student papers on Ford (Box 5)
    - Packet: Student papers on Ford (Box 5)
    - Packets (6) re Norton critical edition of Lord Jim (Box 5)
    - Loose materials re Norton critical edition of Lord Jim (Box 5)
    - Envelope of photos and illustrations (Box 5)
    - Justin Watson's MA thesis on Conrad with cover letter to Moser 1990 (Box 5)
    - Set of proofs for Lord Jim (Norton critical edition) with Moser's letter 1995 (Box 6)
    - Heinemann's Lord Jim paste up (Box 6)
    - Wuthering Heights proofs (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Conrad, Achievement and Decline, proofs (1 folder, 1 envelope) (Box 6)
    - Lord Jim – footnotes and glossary (Box 7)
    - Lord Jim – editor's note on composition and correspondence proofs (Box 7)
    - Lord Jim – textual history (Box 7)
    - E. Sullivan's last corrections and correspondence 1994 (Box 7)
    - Textual notes (Box 7)
    - Lefranc and Sullivan essays (Box 7)
    - Conrad's correspondence re Lord Jim – proofs (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous Moser correspondence (Box 7)
    - Course reader: Conrad and Faulkner, Engl. 388C, Prof. Moser, Winter Quarter 1990/91 (Box 7)
  - The following are Moser's notes as student or teaching assistant:
    - 16th and 17th century literature (Box 7)
    - 18th century literature (Box 7)
    - 19th century literature 1948 (Box 7)
    - Medieval English language and literature (Box 7)
    - Engl. I quizzes 1951-52 (Box 7)
    - Crackanthorpe notes (Box 7)
    - Engl. I old quizzes 1950-51 (Box 7)
    - Notes (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - Undergraduate papers by Moser (3) 1947, 1949 (Box 7)
    - Orals questions & Tutorial bibliography (Box 7)
    - Freshmen advising materials 1952 (Box 7)
    - Comp Lit 362 précis; bibliography of Russian novelists; Hour Exams (Harvard) (Box 7)
    - Eng. 200 & 300 – notes, handouts (Box 7)
    - Comp. Phil. 275 notes (Box 7)
    - Pitt themes (Box 7)
    - 2 packets of note cards (Box 7)
    - Typescripts of Albert J. Guerard's The Exiles and of other Guerard articles, along with remarks on AJG at his retirement (by Moser?) (Box 8)
    - Unsorted materials mostly on the Lord Jim edition (Box 8)
    - Lord Jim proofs (Box 9)
    - Assorted packets re "Good Soldier" publication (Box 9)
    - OS galleys of Lord Jim [18 x 14 flat box] (Box 10 os)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2008-185
  - Incoming Correspondence, 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Incoming Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Incoming Correspondence, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Incoming Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)